

Jan Füchtener Web Developer

About me

I enjoy creating things that live on the internet, whether that be websites, applications, or anything in between. My goal is to always build products that provide pixel-perfect, performant experiences.

In my freetime you will probably find me on a yoga mat or playing handpan.

Contact

- Zum Hoover Feld 13 50170 Kerpen Germany
- +49 1573 3145798
- jan@fuechtener.eu
- https://fuechtener.eu
- https://github.com/Fruchtix

Skills

- ➤ React.js ➤ JavaScript (ES6+) ➤ HTML & CSS
- ➤ React Native ➤ Firebase Git
- Wordpress MySQL > Figma

Education

2012 - 2017

Europagymnasium Kerpen

 Advanced courses in computer science and math

2017 - 2020

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)

- Dual Studies of Information Science for Business (dt. Wirtschaftsinformatik) @FHDW
- Software Engineering as study course specialisation

Experience

CEO & Founder



2019 - ongoing

Helped thousands of people to improve their eyesight and overcome lovesickness through my Apps EyeYoga and Breakup.

- Established companys in response to marketplace demand.
- Learned to design UI and to build projects from start to finish.

Front End Developer (Freelance)



Worked for one of the biggest yoga retreats in spain (Suryalila) and supported a team of 8 people to organize an online yoga summit. I was responsible for the marketing and building the website as well as the actual livestreaming of the event.

Software Engineer @nexible



2019 - 2020

Wrote my bachelor thesis about the user authentication process within the nexible chatbot and programmed it afterwards. Also trained and improved the chatbot and learned more about machine learning.

Software Engineer @Ergo



Worked in a couple of different departments and looked into the processes behind a big insurance company. Got first hand experiences with Scrum and Kanban. Coded with COBOL, C# and used the Elastic Stack to analyse what websites employees are visiting.